picture logging c_r_t_ channel
there's another
sneaky way didn't set up the ir c jail
and i'm not going to go into a live in
the notes if you want to try it out
inside the max
it's in one of the videos and we'll show
you that in a minute
close at this because in the state over
switching today
prices can be lecture nine today
recover
you more fun things out burger actually
fingertip use q g_i_s_
bugler
and brings see a movie in firefox if we
can get to it
so i'm hoping
moved from the land of getting things to
sort of settled in the morning you're
aware on unix to you
genius india
to go ahead and go see the research
tools
webpage
initially a few new things on this web
page to start off with
hope with a lot of pure out
one of which is
playlist here on the two nd i've set up
supporters for videos i've reported that
are basically screencasts where i use
the computer
a record of the screen so you can see
all my mouse movements you can see a
screw-up
hope they don't mumble too much but i
don't have it does it all
it shows me goin thru d max using the
keyboard
trying to avoid the mouth of the first
one completely
and in the later one that you use the
mouse some blank or try to walk through
some of the major topics with imax if
you're feeling uncomfortable with
you can always go back and
take a look at those
and refresh your brain on a mac you
haven't
if you're in trouble typing
i've started
screen captures
i'm creating screen captures and
one of the new things on here
if we look you're on the right
lecture eight which was last week
actually radar screen where ever they
grab my screen every few seconds
and i created pediatrics about fifty
slides for the class
so you can see what was on the screen if
you're listening to the audio he can
bring up there's a pediatric keno and
the power point
and i just had screen grabs you can see
what it looked like
let me start up for this class
snouts capturing
so if i go too fast
you guys just only because it's also
marketing reported only does every ten
seconds
supply goes in and through something
like this silence them
captured material
so here are the four videos thirty years
that playlist you can see them
individually
alterna flow the actual video files so
you can happen to you
uh... i want to be able to take this
with you at the end of class so we're
going to be in the semester
this material is supposed to help you
for the rest of your
facially all technology
what else is going on here so there's
community you too
uh... the audio files
and
so what we need to be today first off
is start off by grabbing
the or go too far for lecture nine
that everyone log into the ir c report
forget
victory say hello
use it for china i can see it
wave your hand if you need any help
if you ask me are seattle peeled seeded
welfare bridgeable there
peso right-click
on this board files
and save link adams
you're up in the senate where ever i
must say that in my home directory
and i'm gonna go over t_v_ mats
since the virtual machines up at the top
ten to hide it be maximum applications
accessories
and then
t_v_ maxwell three
now if you max ever gets completely
stuck during class today
feel free to just kill it
and reopen it go find the file again and
that's our report we left off
sometimes
there's mode that we don't fully
understand yes we're going to race
and we'll get stuck
your frequent back close button kilotons
we'll get right back into it
familiar open that file
news directory edit modem you control x
control at
for find file
you're also welcome to use the menus
an oppressed answer
aman
to a control asked for search
and tight
nine in a dash
and the control of to keep going until i
see it so here's my bash scripting dot
org
momentum acres big because
where are we doing
most of our stuff indymac sam and trying
to keep you guys focusing the maximum
last were popping up
bugler q g_i_s_ or firefox two policemen
and results
returns day as much as possible inside
of the tech center
so today
we're going to go through
creating
sitting at work babble
forest which is promoting safety max
workload
or we can actually run code from what
were writing
so imagine writing like a word document
your second paragraph is actually code
be put on an actually runs
you are in our office
reading that kind of thing here
and we're gonna look at it though that
they don't make it
report model
yet would you be dues control expert
relapse
fear before syria no his enter for the
current electorate
and seeing it as well with the arrow
keys
so it's easier to use these days
so you get down to the line
an opera singer yugioh now if you have a
split screen
control acts and i don't want to
if you were on split the screen
patrol acts
split
and pretty soon you guys are going to
use this
indeed
witty here
officer
prisoner stuff fewer good better step by
having here
sits at the four manning the table of
contents
it's just to make it look nicer
doing it but you're afraid of what
part
ear and
yet so everybody out
will see that part of the home of the
planet
so quickened whenever you want to keep
now tight control x one and i would only
when i left
it's the ones i was like hey i'm
coming back
okay hoping to sell
you can also just you can't relax
controller
now has entered
scroll down to the nine
not now with malice toward the keyboard
or yet but i want
but now
uh... you don't want these to not file
rather than the org final
about your web browser
so make sure that you're not going to
html file
there's a little org link on our rights
right click on the or blank
say that way
and that's the link do you want to use
the html files for formatting step that
will help you out
unless you want to do it in firefox
see that work thing
perfectly
click the mouse built
scenes like this
and that's it
give now remember if you guys are
indirect re-edited rodent
in imax surfacing illegal here
if your direct retailers out-of-date
press g and it will refresh the
directory listing
things like that
over here he max
control x controller
it's her with the number ninety what's
your number
dispersed nine
and then origin
and out of control acts one
i would highly recommend
spots taking the max is figures you can
recently
okay it's a great question so much time
as we started off and we have for the
same violence you've used so email
agitated
what would it then if you have one
window open
three-c_d_ of detroit's once we have
about three one
then you do a control acts
with the number two and that split canal
split it and i mean the same
same file here in here
forty one to you
control acts
three battle split this way so cut
left and right doing too much too late
for this market that
depress the g_m_ had a refresher
and now do you control lasts
detroit's wong
okay now do not mind dash
yay
so go ahead and if you control x one
sealed letter
making actually the full screen
without the possibility is to go before
spring with the max
press liturgy
no control
says the letter g_
so now as you see disappearance
if you all their control it's something
totally different so anti red nose if
you want a refresher courses in just
type g
throughout school for that
nine
took on it yet
and then do you control x one
in almaty
tickles i highly recommend
before thursday take a look at those
videos
there about an hour and fifteen minutes
uh... watching me go through it so you
can seize werder powell
i work with
he max and get a refresher of all the
commands
i try to save them as i do them
over the first one
i ran the gas after putting all the
little
youtube labels up careful i types of the
first ones got some of those labels for
about fifteen minutes
so hope will help you it'll show what
keys i typed azide tatum
here's a link to or babble
which is their really help us out for
the rest of class
will skip that pass that
talked about the extra content videos i
did our model after this web site called
shown me do u
so there's lots of other videos there if
you're interested in
all through the summer style
the warranty right now is we're going to
set up
or gravel
this is going to let us run coincided he
max
so you'll be able to run the examples
that the better in the class notes
without leaving the cost notes
and if we do it right now
there's the key stroke is right here is
control c controls the inside of the
code block
you're going to get an air of the books
like
this line
right here forces no or battle execute
function for passage
for the crazy message
but if i
complex begin
sewers s_h_
and source
anna type
echo
i'm gonna go ahead impressed control c
control c
this is going to have to do i want to
run this code
and if you don't give up on this one
don't worry too much but with a lot of
us today
but at the word yes
press center
and it worked
it shows that our message
unfortunate looks like i set up my team
except for after
fund set up
so we'll have to work
or right when i didn't
if you go down to the scheme excellent
section amanda split my window into
and
in this one
the top one hundred
press on link you next so i lecture
linked to
by using the till two slash documents
i've linked to your docking max
so if you but i don't think you're going
to go to a different file than me
but the product i hope
that david hale
and i'm don't look at them act i don't
listen pretend i'm starting back in the
beginning with you
your daddy max will look like this it
will be nothing it may say something
about the file doesn't exist
so that'll put anybody max
and you have a file with empty or
doesn't exist
we're gonna go copy
everything in this block and says begins
towards the maxwell's
this is a configuration file but i don't
want you to worry about
the idea here is
it should have any max which have
already set up
that were sent a copy
so control space on the first line
angus is now highlighting of them down
her right before the end source
an oppressive skate kiefer medha
and then
w_-four copying
and i'll say the whole bunch of texts
control acts
and then old
also is also clear that there are
multiple ways to do it
figured hold adults
and then press the keys
soem added that he was copied
taking it stuck
flagrant
so control likes to display your window
the number two
and so then you can click on that saudi
max file
see those arguments now you can use the
mouth of the combat
and see why
is bank
any pics
who's actually got it
got a couple to texas her package
by the end of this clock next one hope
we're so be it
will keep doing a lot of stuff
c keep their begin anne and efforts the
out of it
antibacterial hotly contest for you
ceded control axle with only one went
over to you split control x two
which will expand the number two
uh... patrol exp to jump to the proper
you can do that file suit yet relaxed
amenity
control acts
amenities
switched a buffer presenter
sedating facing there
pace this year
based if you want to say that you get a
good for the menu or its control
extension elasticity
and feel free typing against those are a
ton into the ir c
things very say they're co-stars so
these are all
she had her first
genesis was that a little bit in this
one has been saved starts at seven
instead as you're going
out yet say that before
control its controls
i message authentic you're stuck
this will help you out
found if you're an owner file his
release
so we don't want to taxing you want for
my gosh i don't want that
here files vince a particular editing
the classic samples and its just
completely messed up
easy ones like you had a big recent
action you papa delete key
acts
any type of reverts
dash offer
say we're command
but what it does
is it says ok i'm gonna go back to the
desk i'm gonna reread the following the
rock all the changes
and start over from the desk
i'll use this one allot
so especially if you're cut copy pasting
isn't something you want to see the
issue of the stuff
seven minutes
hold on hold
assets
well insulation that acts that type of
birds
dash buff
pressed for time
insist you hurt
state that
yes
gang about the original file options
are having trouble copying
so go to the beginning of one where
you're at this some important
yet so
yet practices depict the keyboard
or for an open house
through going to go back up to where you
the documents section
so to control it when i would put away
the mask the mouse is just too much
trouble
the control act
another one
control acts
and then get the number one
scroll down the therapy is just easier
unskilled
these unique in that section
okay separated here
broke up with some important after the
begin down
yet right there
control space
mark set up a good
now easier please
silicon scroll down
see i'll tell you know
now do you want to be right above
the and source
netcom online
hit escape
i'd like to know
now as they choose to the same this
matter
now do that
w for the car
corner copy that
espresso w by itself
go open that he makes possible quickly
thing
without snowing affected
correct
going here
put them there
many things do you have a text scoop
and you can't relax and uh... oh
control space
dinner down
now do you anticipate
w copy
controller acts
over to get the other window
paperback o'quinn
and i want to control
why paste
says there is now down to the files
the copy one-line too much to me
you don't feel that in this mini button
no presidential he quit
control d
you know it was but the problems
select your documents
and it's a matter
so hold on alts and mentally
and now huang and control why every day
it's a bit file for controllers control
as that's set out on that
closing acts for dot
ideological as the max
for every story is he's way to reload
this configuration file so we can set up
imax
so they can now run source code for its
inside
hang in there guys we're almost there
saumya
and just you file
quick or control act controls the
it might ask you a lot of questions
uh... dossier by dot you max
and you see mine
okay so can't relax control c
you may ask you yes no
and you have to answer of based on what
you've got
and restore enacts
we're all gonna see
who succeeded
hopefully all of us
to restart the max now it should have
gravel opens
so i can you control its control after a
moment ago nine dash
fifty-odd
anna re-open
that bash script
dot org
yet you can spread swine is asking do
you wanna saves at this moment
then
uh... here if you will see an inferno
yet
uh... type yes you do you want his name
linked to the white yes
okay now restarting max
goodfellow wasn't there
if you open up that poor quality that
got
from the bottom
greatest roll back down to where we were
and still right below
that bid attached
and there's the second year control how
bring since the middle
drug-testing section
we're gonna tell us what's going on here
got going there to try the past
its control c controls the inside of
that
echo shell commands
uh... you've opened up a different file
minute you put up of so can't relax in
the mccain
their little world
and control t
i was going to do secretaries angie just
validity
it just just emailed control
separate file press center
affect your kids and after all of the
testing section
control team
and wants is the head of the directory
that would be easiest
control expert romance
once once
for excellence
now in just a reminder performances and
working
you think you were
whose now you have a lot of different
prompt so you must acquit someone
slightly different
picnic
oftentimes is going back through it
needed something you'd like to prompt if
you'd realize or
unanswered for testing
your in highly mobile was apologetic
reasons of price controls place
turns on and off the highlighting
abrasions
searches for
this role as a searching within the text
of the screen seems open the file
so control team to quit square
now open up if you are a search for you
can do culpepper home directory so
controllers controller
control asserts control acts as an x-ray
yeah wasn't fun
helpers internal when you're home
directory
since looks more like it make it
really wide
and now see how you have
so they can click on that panel
negative control x one
so what we need to do now is a test
archos
make sure that were actually able to run
up road blocks obispo blockage is going
to print out which show were using
we'll get into variables in a little bit
what will doom as you go inside of the
source walk
going here
not since i've got hi leon i can turn
that off
control space
and i'm now
in the middle as echo
and rain here
there's the evils lines which are just
saying that the sick of block
project controls he controls the inside
of a code section and will undercut
to control c
control c
have to say that we like to run this
country always check with you make sure
it's okay
what side yes because we really do want
to run this current
and what you should see is a little bit
extra pure afterwards concerns
out plus results
and then it returns that
michelle is actually and slash batch
if you have a text
great that you don't
now as your cursor inside of the cold
war
you got the highlights of ethnic groups
are inside
control c control c
yes
fantastic
so break their urine that belong you
could have a control al animal center
the tax
perfect okay now
go into that begin source
now you can you control c controls the
inside of that for for
type gas you want you
presenter
that's great
ideological what's it like
look like the one thing to watch of
course there's these little commas
insider this workbook that i have
that's trying to hide some stuff from
working
for that
you now have a working
ord double setup inside and so we can
run code from inside a more violent
and we're now used and to create a log
file
and we're going to go user dropbox
account filings we spent a lot of time
working on dropbox we get to use it fine
so grow inside of the begins source
s_h_
maker
dropbox
and what this will do is going to create
directory inside of your account called
logs
underneath dropbox
so control c
control scene is probably a complaining
because
i did this really are
best guess
aniket created because our team pictures
for me hopefully for you and i'll say
nothing
am i complain saying the cold war
returned happen
if you saw that
yun
have something else where
say
tenure
play checking
depicted nothing
basically make your doesn't print
anything when it succeeds it only
complaints it's it's a complex
it doesn't tell you a good job
appreciably so what major works it's
quite
planned it didn't work it from being
first talking abt u
so i for me is that i can make that
directory
that bad
finalize actually okay because
irish factory
and i would probably it because i really
have a lot file puddle actually
now we have a another will script any
rabbit at this one before you run it
in here
it's going to
use a little bit rex we gotta worry too
much about the variables to later on
today
might go into the scripts and here it's
going to find a variable called log
leave her place
your username
so not in my case
that's gonna be
that's shwarier your case it'll be
whatever your
short secom active directory windows
account name
and what this will do it's gonna set a
variable with your log file
it's going to
echo breakup of the screen a startup
show all this is going to keep warm up
from collapsing your log file and i
think
when you're beginning you'll see show
walls and almost all my documents
because
pressing attack he claps in hyd
some of the uh... sections in or motives
really clever
but it's also very confusing you open up
a document the you know it's like
thousand lines long and you'll see three
lines in the books
people cannot file so
bradshaw
and then if there is a
that redirect and so if you have to
remember from before
a greater than symbol
and then a file name
is going to write that data into that
file
so terribly that one morning into our
logfile
so if you've got back with your name
press control c
controls the run this block
yes
my hair when you have nothing in it so
life is good
and let's go open
your log file
miss what this uh... that too
with control lax and number two
and we'll do a control x control out
from reading or finder logfile is
created
so it's d_r_ capital t_ orchids are
press tab
it should complete the drop box
till now after he called logs
and then
there will be something called
research tools
lasting like that
three two three five different
thirty are a little bit sorry
what you're doing good
and then
see you open up partially true with
going
to build a bear i had dropbox law the
sand and research tools alive
controllers controller
and then logs
slash
okay lynch you don't have a working
dropbox on gamefaqs leaning
dingy going
so i just mea dropbox doors before he
hasn't really dropbox in seal will
needed work ethic lost a fixture dropbox
extra boxes like lightning so now i've
got my log file here guys
it's blankets are very exciting
but if you look down below
ever see a lot of this results stuff
coming along
it likes to put it into a table
even though a dozen or so they make
sense
so here
it took the output of the log file
and just dumped
the echo and in the capital files and
stuck his tax from the file
land there
you'll get use that over time
it's a little weird
and what this file is this is actually
your homework assignment for that
dressed of the semester
every day here in here
we shouldn't be homework it's actually
in classwork
so hopefully but i mean what you're done
with this
what i want to do is create a log entry
for each day than your ins class
and you have built up and work mode log
where you can keep notes about
things in this class that you are now in
addition to us in the class notes
so this is a place for you to keep notes
banking here than that you want to add
to which need to know
and i've got some instructions in here
for example
we need to copy n
the title of the author of the email i
could have been the homework to you
so few controls basin here scroll down a
little bit
and then do another
medha w_-two copying
in the control like so
and paste
and then you can go ahead and fill in
your name
and
in the title
and your name in the author
and you know
this is these are notes that are men
from a really for you know and making
you do this so you would see it once
and you are welcome to our this class is
done never do this again if he so
desired
but if you like if you're free to keep
going
now remember if you want to kill thin
line good beginning of a line here
press control k
an appeal to the info on
night pace y
collapse that exception
so if you see three dots after a section
it means you clocked at with the tab
keith
and economic lots that with the tax
return
you can also be lameta x river proffer
if you want just undo all your changes
river proffer as your friend
to them that it w
twine
v
yeah you have three daughters into the
garden burger c
so scroll for that
it's detroit so
and first time
went out again
but we don't believe this slots that
you don't have very fancy featured the
continuation times
so you're building a national one that
there's the examples if i put it example
in there
i don't want to set my title separating
those force walk saying this is work
mode source
so you can actually talk about yourself
almost in work
it's a little weird
because things keep asking those kinds
of questions those are great questions
let's go ahead and create a log entry
synergy one of these for each day
failure in class
the way you do it is a top level entry
with just a start
you can take whatever you want
for the tax to describe that day
in my log entries i tend to write
what part of the country and then in the
united states
what date is that you can say whatever
you want to say that research
tools
lecture
phone line
and then i insert the date
so that i can figure out what they did
this happen on
and u_s_ control sea and the puri in
insert that date
and that's our full stop
and then you can press center or if your
computers on the wrong date and the rest
of your homeworks that by using virtual
machines that are going to sleep in
olive figure out what
date is
in a future lecture also you guys how to
update the clock
but for now
just make sure you're on the right day
if it says like sunday this problem not
being caught doing tonight
you can just click on that you want
what we can do then actresses tag it
with control c
control c
times are
anything you want them to be
their way to mark things without
structure
and you can come back and grab all the
injuries which occur tag
hi used
date
for all my day entries
controls the control c
yeah how do you have to have the cursor
on that entry line
letting you know i watch of course
control c control c does lots of
different things
and i actually don't know what it does
and so i don't get somewhere i need it
to michael yet the trophy control c
it's sort of like the do next thing
saliva where our checkbox
anyone to check it off you tight control
c control c
so for example
many presidential you're gone
but if i've been down here
and i did um...
i'm working on an injury
answer controls the control c
that tunnels the flags of the same
keystroke
in a different place in a different
meaning it's the next
you want a conduit change this one
serb-controlled g one more time to quit
so you get your game
sieving control acts
abby by itself first which buffers
became a tab it'll give you a list of
offers
and see from what comes to mind
you can either
press nine thousand
senator
there's a question that here
you have a few minutes with eighties
highbrow stuff it's the same religious
text
fish is helping you formatted nicely
kentucky
you can use to left square brackets
please please correct it
right
okay the way attacked works is that
battalion entering
anything underneath it is included in
the day
so if i can write
this is included in day
an entry that's included i have to date
agnostics anything in their inherits
that you can on inherited
now we can also say is
if we note that now we have a tag by
press deanne and tab
it will complete backpack
so what you've got times
it'll actually start
so to put talking here
for just a random one
jump idea control c control c
and i proceed to united talent
it says it's tackled a tag call todd
and you know and i wasn't
about tags
so you can build up tanks
that are based on your research or
things worked on
you can't act like the case and you can
do whatever you want with your tags
and later on search them
the way you feel like it
so they don't have to be related to
anything
you can mix and match is a go
so you've seen those like blues
boxes around stuff ford says things
what this is um...
so if i do
to the class notes
see others up blue box from logging
and testing
further tags
so you can actually say
i'd like to see the document
only with these tax shelling
there's a um... all sorts of fancy
searching you can you can also write
code later on
to grab tags out and do stuff
and you get the insecure ownership you
could tag things with
what you're doing what kind of job you
had you could tag him with that position
tied like
pieper surveyed
solely up to you how you can do that
so that will actually be a part of your
homework and i said it was the first day
of why don't we go ahead make that two
speedy tuesday help change the notes in
rio love them
for each day
you're gonna need to creatine entering
for that day
at the bottom of this
entry at the bottom of page
there's actually a homework assignment
so if we go back to it
to hear me click on that
if you look at the table of contents
warm one says homework
that was basically to have you going to
journal entries
but the mobileme server and then let me
see them so make sure you guys are
comfortable making entries working with
a log files on your own
so there'll be a homework sections of
autumn where it says to do homework
deadline
i'm gonna change this
to be next week
so tuesday
and partner who has watched the video
tutorial go through
exactly this stuff
you know about the basics if you watch
the videos they'll go through more of
its again creating entries
moving around he boarded
asking questions if he needs more time
and you need some help other classes let
me know will set up a time
let's go
use what we've got now
create
some project
telescope creative laura k nl
of some actual data
investors will see if we can get
shipwreck
upon the screen
already used workload with double as
much as we can
to run for the examples you get to see
them we don't have a tight too much
and you can excuse me as you go see the
responses
see how it's going
scroll down to this first entry where
it's going to make a directory
cancellous what's in this directory
warranted here is going to make their
dash piece ingrid we're gonna make more
than one director at the same time
we're gonna make a class directory we'll
rent in each of our class assignments in
and this lecture is nine fourteen
city rat control c
control c_n_n_
and that's good you know a listing of
what's in that
who put that directory looks like some
yes
what i've done here
the dash d
with al at says don't go inside any
directories social media directory
itself
so here's our home richard tools manipal
history
racism
the log file as your notes
you what you have to write them
is not an automatic right now
out maybe it gerald
were clogged
so this will reduce you examples and you
have to take on a day-to-day work and
then we'll get into the details
using control ad zero or you can control
like to be
this was what was
first-time
things are all the wolf as you can you'd
like
decline with too
apace that exploring
we treated at directory and what we can
do with what was the head open it will
do a control extn
and then control expert rollout
class
sparsh
or nine
press and tear
and there's nothing in there
control x control have to find a file
yet
and then open up a directory
so class phone line
if you look up your
since they were half so you should all
now have any thoughts slash from nine
so this is all of that magic
would work but it's going to be a little
weirder first
but you can write
in what you were typing a command line
and read from your document
and if your require rerun it you just
press control c control see again that
code block into overdrive
i think is a little mystical sounding
anything as a buffer yes
we have a lot of our person of the
questions
this one that represents the class notes
matches the file
so that is this fire over here
and you can say that it will be saved
this is also a proper
mac following a directory
if that's ok with a directory
project presents he has heated rhetoric
changes afsane
about first look at the end memory
and
uh... u
yet have offers attached to a file you
can say
if you look you're advocating couldn't
find out who filed a sarcastic is the
hope
support in this window
makefile
savings parade out and i'm not really
sure what to say that is going to do
i don't want to read it
some things you could you don't always
make sense
in the past we've them in running a lot
of commands from the command line
in tightening now
for example use curl to go and get stuff
and what i've got here is the source
code block
that's going to
change directories into this thus far
as their only to finance
for his commands
you get a raise the curl memory ran last
time
to go grab a your whole
so we had
eager to return you get
so did you get it was the one that was
driving me crazy
i kept having problems
curl does all of the same thing
with a slightly different
syntax
that i seem to get wrong less often
curls gonna go out gravity or out and
save it to you
wherever it's at
suffer joined here and we do a control c
control c
and evaluate this code block
press yes
that's the best go
that says output to the same file name
as is and that you are out
sister actually doing
we go over here
lefty
and magically to files appear two night
directory
controlled she's quite g
is director of fresh
to give you guys a sense of what this is
like
if i copy this you are a lot this
grab a beer thank you amanda x shall
for now i'm in terminal
so i mean that same directory
com and delete everything there so i'm
gonna be careful here
started in rome
so i can do
this could be a little bit of a work
packing go grab that file
and it will get the file
what i almost didn't
well most of the screen saver as a
directory you can say that listing as a
final
and so that's eating it looks like to
read but it was just a file
yes or a text file directory listing so
if it's very confusing for free
the pearl was not found
yourself at the terminal
and do you know
ciskei install
besitos based apt-get space install
space
so once you're in interact mode any when
the command
activity read window for there
the nine directory
support inside on the window
i'm impressed g
directory in it
uh... so you can look to control what to
do this but you're going though
campus and i can't relax be dismissed
offers
does everyone to me
fear in the class treasury so scroll
down to the nine
you can click on the line there
now do
okay g run the command
to go get those two finals
yet into the makers of elmore
see that rain right there with the two
get files
yet to put in their not you don't become
a green light at the federal state and
yet
andia controls the controls the
type yes to evaluate that long
protector
here the other window patrol acts in or
yet
within a pristine
to control acts to you
to split the window
attracts them to you
and now open up that directory so
controllers controller
and see how this is uh...
classes lined class
slash going on
than empty faster
uh... probably i think the key to it but
i don't know enough to help my head in
my piano teaching
if you look on their or you can do it
control x one eight one foreign split
nitpick
there's i think the key for everything
but i don't think yet
severe remember edirectory edit mode
it's not going to look at the desk again
and tell you actually perfect kiki
to refresh the page
and it would not have achieved files
downloaded
without balloting files
these two files
aman career on that so that i'd get them
to files constituency
yes
thank you gene update
these files our little bits of x_ amount
you don't have to go look at them all to
show you real quick
at the beginning and ending is other
came out file and we're going to get
into the full details of what i cannot
file looks like
but for today
don't think too much about what it is is
just a container it's gonna container
ship tracks
and if we put the beginning of fronts
we put our points for our ship track in
the middle
and fifty and on the back
then we'll have a file that will be able
to view
and people are will spend a whole bunch
of time to learn a lot of camo
throughout the semester
but for now it's what you be able to
actually see one on the screen
the next set of instructions are going
to you as we go through
will go grab those
we also need to get now the data
that's gonna go in there so whatever
done as i've taken a ship track from a
construction ship bottle boss and that
was building a billion dollar
natural gas terminal
ends the track of a ship for a little
while
during this time he's building it
so let's go ahead and run the section in
the past
we grabbed a farce ultimately randy owns
it to you
this is going to do it for us so it's
going to go and ryan
versus can change that directory
and then it's going to go brown
that file with
we've been curl command
and help with that
creating long parliament is getting a
bit of csd and i'm going to look at see
if you like we've done for other files
it's gonna be ends it to you that file
compressor so let's go ahead here on
this block
to control c
control c and yes
goes really fast and actually on campus
if in fact g after
out you should now see
two thousand seven boston construction
dot csd
you can put on if you want and open up
it's a whole bunch of
ship positions sellers acts
wanted to
spi latitude
others tell you don't have to notice
right now this is a unique to you can
see timestamp
it's the number of seconds since
nineteen seventy
how's that for us funky
it's actually a really great number have
it works very well as just
kind of strange winemaking seventies
beginning of time
but it makes working with time to
preview for other examples will use it
will have
at times lighter
that's a great question why did why we
have to see everyone
we could have put the word file in the
class directory
but we didn't have a class directory yet
that she would work together in the same
directory
but here or twyla somewhere else on the
desk
filled working directory for the script
is always working or files
so we have to get to working area
and they could be some stuff to the
files
every time we start
see those two stars
even adding a spiral
you can just to control x zero
immediately
and be in the background for it
command control ex to you and you can
put something else and
kellogg's to and inspect
going to buffers
and pick everyone that you can take the
class and
useful
an impressive g
if you had to file a stock
intellectually deflect overly easily
financed if you want to save them
ballard uncompressed this
bunch of data
so i'll put it up
i'm not sure why sometimes it up with
the best the program going during the
file for you
uh... already exists
okay secret twice
if you run
the ends it
the second time you've done with these
beings in it'd be easy to file and your
t_v_ unzipped died csd file
there's now a csd file their annual on
compressing destroyed file
it's it's ok in light of easy to follow
and
them without
and so
open up your directory
just click on the top an insult buffers
press g
i think that politically
and see how you have a csd dot easy two
ciency winters and compress that was the
right that violence is
that will work
if you want to leave the file
you can always
select the file press the de ke when
you're on it you see that the ama left
their interns red
and by pressing acts it's going to win
it
you can also get you
animal
takeaway acctually flag
deeper julie
without the job
now i've got a few commands and we need
to troy's one
made by windows takeover
let's take a quick look at that file
three scripts so if the water on the
head like we normally would see the
first time lines
within your control c controls the in
there
but yes
know that i've got
example but i've been there is what you
should see something come like that
and now it's going to write the results
if we have a peer
those results if it's going to write out
the first time lines
now it's going to end table form
often pretty good
you know if if you want to have this as
a table you can bend megan i stable yet
you're out external file
i needed to go
so we've got some nice data
we can reuse that country and that we've
talked about the past
ground felt a lot to learn a lot of two
nd into our party hacks and why it once
was
here's a sample wanna see what the cut
with you
track dash d fertile amader recht rot
palma
the comma
so the comma separated values
dash f says which feels we want to keep
want to keep the first film second field
so that'll be
something like
those first two for each line
and memories going to take the first
time lines with the head command
you you've been drinking beer science
classes so upset by phone
command-line stuff people have writing
this cut command
we're not picking my computer scientists
so they start on wife one
mhm
peewee actually open up with uh...
at the imax into book and their buffet
hopeless
i would have been very veteran had
command
internet
thank you participate jump back at us
etc
yes typically heads
you don't you'll notice especially with
brown scientists
settlement and sometimes it's completely
narrowly weird
where people here don't think that's the
right time for chapter all
some of them that dot all some of the
pink dot can be in a number
the extensions can be also whatever you
want
so let's go ahead and run this cut just
to see it real quick
controls the control c
and many others
will get table with just the first two
columns
so the longitudinal i_t_n_
at matches
this is what really is in the file
and missus uh... or babble playing with
it turn the table for us
we're really lucky in this case because
came out once for a wine
is it wants
are header so we have a header file to
respect on there
and you're not going to look in their
you don't care what's in their we want x
come alive
an ex-con why and then r_k_o_ that's
separate from the end
so we're gonna go with those three files
together and we're going to have a valid
cannot file rhino that doesn't mean very
much yet
but i want you to see your working him
now
what that's going to look like here's a
quick sample was one of the school what
we will have the same spot placemarks
burden of building a place markham with
the line
the corn it's
and this is what we're sticking in the
middle
acts comma y
anyone ex-con why anymore and i'm not
this appears to back to what we want
what we have down here as we have that
same cut command
marinis that redirection again
that great of a m
to write to exhaust ex-wife i'll
dot ex-wife
i think that because it tells me that
there's an accident why
so scott had more on this one
control c control c
type yes
he went off and it's a stopover go back
trolex q
control x
and open up the zero nine directory
press the letter g_
and i now have an ex-wife i'll blow my
csd
so control exited his flat
and then control exited penelope by
itself without
this was proper
it doesn't say zero nine
the pizzas arrive presenter
dividends as there are profound and
energy to refresh the window
time to make
okay now let's actually working came out
and let's go buick
so this growth just a little bit here
so in the past we've just done
greater than
and that will always step on whatever's
there so we will delete anything that
already exists
but we want to or can't
and there's a special
thing for that and that's
to greater bands
file name
this means apparent
or add to so it's gonna keep adding on
to the file
every time you get one of these are
following it's gonna
overwrite
and get rid of anything there before
if we do file name
to have these it's gonna add on to the
end of that file keep ticket water
soares de car three files
we're gonna first do over at once
screening file
and they were in a penny twice
so first for intake are headed
so first
we're gonna cap which is don't all the
text of the screen
google earth winds start dot came out
where he is the single greater band
to create a new file called it
aren't you done seven boston
construction
animal to a head
more difficult problem because otherwise
his
google earth inside a virtual machine
terribly happy
and will give our
dot ex-wife i'll to greater vans and
then ok na file
analytic detail
those locked or here that the odds and
d'aquino
he presented and on the entrance to the
stick together everything
if you've done that go ahead an open up
here to record and do it you can see if
you can see your file
so you're not you're in fundamental mode
as opposed to address rating to control
like this
you'd indicated feel
uh... center
and then
control like this
came to know
the singer
yes
and now your interview
you have the acting opened up that's
fine
let's go ahead and
so i'm gonna go run this command
control c control c
yes
control ext two and then control exp
interflora marin
pit g
and i now have a k_-mart file
i'm not gonna look in there we're gonna
hope that it's right and i'm just
working people
let's go ahead and open up a terminal
that acts shell
hope will open the airplanes directory
if not you can see the till two slash
class
slash from nine
google dash earth
to go ahead and do their yeah go ahead
with it
here over the realtor r u doing freddie
mac who can excel
if you open a google earth
don't put anything just yet
then you need to cdc i had a cd command
ret of other
cd till the slash
terminal right up here
yet with excel
or if you fully for getting in the
middle of like
crunch time for work
hugest open up a terminal older one
different matter
after about two thousand times maybe
yet it's one of those uh... it takes a
while
if you start to learn
you're gonna see a warning probably
fell to the warning and looks way better
than ever has a very weird
you're gonna see anti warning at the
taxes that he basically unreadable
i apologize i don't know why might
accept me is readable that's pretty
awesome i wish i could reproduce that
cricket no
you don't wanna run in three d mode
because it may crash right now
diversity isn't the greatest for
graphics
i admit it but no
uh... mine crashed allow
amader tries to get your report
package if you guys
you can close the test results that the
other
sister res
terminal
cv
so i have to go to leeds
the talk to all ur
class
that look so pretty
salmon steak you will
singer and a harbor girl terminal
and said no
democratic
close to close at all times
and now you have a global point
delayed file
yay
t_v_ and your congregation
effect cd
or totally do it
are in
now you're very careful dash or us
space
dot g
untapped
if there's a google earth there not be
any spaces or any extra characters
absolutely all that's gone
now 'cause cv minus to go back to roll
directory
and using it pretty clear the space
between the cv reminders
okay now tied to the lord of the sender
uh... with the next time we'll keep you
g_i_s_
and there is a shipwreck a boston harbor
which looks terrible and at a local
cases
so that's what you should see
deal or it seems to be very unhappy with
the virtual machine pepsi neighboring
analytics another machines in the
building and it went great
i think it's just a virtual machine set
up the graphics are a little
were still trying to figure that part
out
will use q g i guess for a lot of our
visualization for a bit
so now we have
to track
from senada
and where to keep working towards
work into your mortgage types doing more
on our system and do a lot of the stuff
coming up and fight on
so gradually little bit more show stuff
on thursday
annemarie estar really using python
because python is where we really want
to be
the shell scripting stuff is just a
means to an end
a pipe bomb what to do
process together
it's difficult to move files around and
whatnot inside a pipe bomb without
known cell
do you watch those videos
yeah i hope they help in about an hour
fifteen minutes you could have caused
replay
of lego so if you can see all the
keystrokes
at radisson and of course i can see you
can follow along
sometimes just
seen couple times being able at had
pause
ticket copy break come back to it
helpful
has logged
so i keep open wednesday that work walk
again
so i'll pick one from last last year
and scroll down a little ways here
so my doctoral crazy 'cause in the
middle of stuff
for example
here was me
making a report from somebody i talk to
you
here's me working with workload
it's really however you want to make
entry
might talk to somebody at j_p_l_
site idea is the guy's name and gpl
as working with some source code
so here's a source code that i wrote
down
working with our server
so it's really however you want to do it
if you want to include all code snippets
if you just when i read a paragraph
about what you did for that day if you
wanna write one signs
it's up to you
how you want to use this as long as an
entry for data during this class
i'm happy for grading
and however you want to use it after
that is totally up to do
so if you want to get down to that is
great
annoying to you and it doesn't work for
your take their work style
they don't use it they've been making
those entries for the homework
we can also include pictures down the
road and i can show you how that
add pictures and your notes
and by being in your drop box
it sorry say that you can get to it from
your desktop
so by being in your your drop box
you can go from here
home computer a former remark for the
dropbox website helvey there
uh... and you can also install dropbox
on windows
without being administrator it won't
work
as well from what i can tell but it
should work pretty well
uh... so you can always go dropbox dot
com under windows machine
install drop boxes user
and get the same files
and that way
were stern develop a place where we can
keep stuff
and if you go back and work from a
different computer you can still see it
feel free to use those nine years
that after the talk
there's a lot of people working as a
minority very fast
in just a few classes
so feel free to go back into
you know if it's
too much
inside of you max feel free to use a
vast save
case you know whatever works for you
returning going
there's lots and lots of commands and
they come with time
productively after force
wearing on that's why there seems to
cheats
a highlighter for the ones that you want
to remember that they're causing trouble
as good thing
at dublin when i was working as i put a
highlighter audit on the ones that i
want to be able to notice for the quick
and uh...
presumption
that word
you just have to have been working
academic used between arnold
when power
they just released vmware fusion for
and they charge us more for i don't know
what
three works great if you've got a copy
of it
yet is active in pricing for vmware
on the mac as the one place you have to
buy a is on the back
outlets and when does the more players
free
if your material others also
uh... virtualbox
uh... which is free it's from oracle
as a free version of a commercial
version with them
it wont not yet
for those of you ever running off a and
there's a
a mode you can turn on
and that's called auto fill
back to you
if you turn on auto fill
and you type in your long sentence it's
gonna rapid back into it
shorter taxed
so i can just keep typing in these
artist junk words
anthony keep going
whether you met a acts
auto
uh... dash bill
so ivory type of because i'm so used to
auto completion
if you present during here
you'll now at the bottom
see phil
and defiant
presses space in that paragraph it's
gonna wrap it for me
so that was
that acts auto
and if you're in the middle paragraph
and you want it
to resort this paragraph is
you have some horrible paragraph
an escape
for reefer truck all that i can have one
so it's my tax auto fill
and then i think you will reap we have
flow that paragraph